Julie Marie Evans

713-447-0724 <u>JULIEMEVANS17@GMAIL.COM</u> KILGORE, TX LINKEDIN | GITHUB | BLOG | PORTFOLIO WEBSITE

PROFILE

Experienced in React, JavaScript, and Ruby on Rails based programming with a background in problem-solving. Possess strong skills in organization and project management that encompasses self-motivation and seeing ideas through to completion. Enthusiastic towards design which helps with styling projects. Great understanding of Linguistics that provides a basis in language learning, including programming languages

EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPER, PINGWIND; CDC CONTRACT MAY.2023-PRESENT

- Implemented "Clean Slate" to reduce excessive files and transition to updated sites with new look and feel.
- Created new BMI Calculators and updated the Alcohol Quiz refreshing the UI, adding features, and improving the functionality.
- Collaborated with team members to run security scans and remediate PDFs to be 508 compliant.

FREELANCE TRANSLATOR, NAQADA STUDIO 2019-2021

- Translated 10 episodes of an anime TV show from Japanese into English.
- Listened to audio from video to aid in translating the Japanese dialogue transcription.

TRANSLATOR, TED CONFERENCE LLC 2016-2018

- Watched videos and translated Japanese dialogue transcriptions into English.
- Time-coded the translated dialogue in sync with audio for subtitles.

EDUCATION

FLATIRON SCHOOL - OCT.2021-SEP.2022

Software Engineering program covering the fundamentals of Full-Stack Web Development.

UNIVERSITY OF NORTH TEXAS; DENTON, TX - JUN.2016-MAY.2020

Bachelor of Arts degree in Integrative Studies with focus in Anthropology, Linguistics, and International Studies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Next JS, TypeScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, SCSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JSON, SQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, and Redux.